A Guide to the Meek Family Papers 1855 (1916-1940) 1944,
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Meek Family Papers 1855 (1916-1949) 1944
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
500-a
This collection consists of ca. 380 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Meek Family Papers were purchased by the Library from Miss Ada Meek of Middlebrook, Augusta County, Virginia on June 30, 1951.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of ca. 380 items (two Hollinger boxes and one oversize folder; ca. 1 linear foot), 1855 (1916-1940) 1944, correspondence, photographs, and miscellaneous material chiefly relating to the Meek, Allison, and McCutchan families. Most of the material pertains to Ada Cordelia Meek of Middlebrook, Augusta County, Virginia. Letters to her refer to family geneology, charitable and mission work, the Presbyterian Church, the Massanetta Springs Summer Bible Conference Encampment, 1926-27, and her small mail order nursery business. Also included are two bound volumes containing genealogical information regarding the Allison and Meek families, an autograph album, 1855-87 of Isabelle Meek, a diary and personal account book, 1861-67, and a sketch of the home of James McCutchan near Middlebrook.
Contents List
- Letters to Ada Meek 1916-1932, 40 items (Box 1)
- Letters to Ada Meek 1933-1939, 34 items (Box 1)
- Letters to Ada Meek 1940, n.d., 26 items (Box 1)
- Postcards to Ada Meek 1909-1944, n.d., 168 items (Box 1)
- Receipts and Bills 1855 & 1879, 1937, 1940, 13 items (Box 1)
- Diary with personal accounts 1861-1867, 1 item (Box 1)
- Religious Materials 1885, 1922 & 1929, 1936, n.d., 13 items (Box 1)
- Invitations 1916-1940, 10 items (Box 1)
- Greeting Cards 1937, n.d. (Box 15 items)
- Miscellaneous Postcards n.d., 16 items (Box 1)
- Autograph album of Isabelle F. Meek 1856-1887 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Materials 1935-1940, n.d., 21 items (Box 2)
- Songs and Poetry n.d., 39 items (Box 2)
- Photographs 1910-1927, n.d., 32 items (Box 2)
- Clippings 1901-1938, 15 items (Box 2)
- The Allison Family, 1714-1941 Vol. 1 1714-1941, Bound volume (Box 2)
- The Meek Family, 1758-1942 Vol. 2 1758-1942, Bound volume (Box 2)
- Items pulled from Volume 1 1897 & 1932, 4 items (Box 2)
- Pencil sketch of house of James McCutchan near Middlebrook n.d.